Friends, do you know that if we get
our bike or scooter insured
through any third party agency or agent, then we may suffer a loss of up to 20 to
25%.  In today's
video, I am going to tell you a very direct
method.  How can you get your bike or
scooter insured
online from the comfort of your home at very cheap rates?
But brother, before taking insurance,
you should always remember three terms.
Whenever we do insurance,
there we have first party, third
party and our comprehensive plan.
So let me
tell you about all three in detail.  These
three things will help you a lot in getting insurance.
So
friends, let's start the program quickly.
So friends, here we will first talk about the
third party plan.  Now look, there are
many people who
purchase only third party plans.
Because third party plans are the cheapest.
Plus, whatever your requirements are under this plan, whether it is to
escape from the police
or to insure your bike, both are
covered.  Then brother, a
question might be coming to your mind,
why do we organize the first party?  So here I will
tell you one of the biggest differences.   For
example, let us assume that if I am going on
my bike and by any
chance I hit someone
or he meets with an accident, then the
third party plan will
save you from the police
and will also insure the vehicle for you,
but the insurance will be only
for your vehicle, only
your third person can claim the insurance.
For example, if my bike causes
damage to the property of someone in front of me or if his
bike or scooter gets damaged, then
my insurance will
provide the claim to the person in front and it will
not be of any use to me.  Only third
party plan can save me from challan.
Whatever loss I incur, I will have to
bear it myself.  And look,
our first party plan here will
also have the same situation.
If I am going with my bike or scooter.  If
I hit someone and
by any chance an accident happens, then the person in
front will also
get the claim and my bike or
scooter will also be provided the claim.  That means
here the
claim is provided to both the parties through my insurance company.
But you all
know that there are some consumer parts inside the bike or scooter
which are
not covered.  But you will get the same cover
in the comprehensive plan.
There you basically have to take add ons.
If you have taken a zero depth
plan or
even a comprehensive plan, then
in any accidental case, if you take a claim, then
here you do not have to pay even ₹1 from your pocket.
So guys I hope it is
clear to you.  Let me
try to tell you quickly once.  If I
take a third party plan then I mean the
police will not issue a challan to me.  But
in case of an accident,
my company will provide the claim only to the other person.
I will not get any claim.
I will also get the claim in the first party case.
I will be saved from the police and the
other party will also get the claim.
Because brother, it is mandatory to meet the opposing party.
You have to keep this in mind.
So the first party is also clear to you.
But if we take a first party
plan and if
we have to make a claim in case of an accident, then there are some
parts which are not covered in the claim.
That is why we have to take a
comprehensive plan or a zero depth
plan here.  This is basically an add on.
Its premium increases slightly
as compared to first party plan.
That is why in our comprehensive plans,
maximum parts of your body are
covered.  Now friends, here
I am going to tell you the most amazing thing.
Listen to this carefully.  Look,
for example, let us assume that if you
buy a new bike or car from the showroom,
you are provided 5 years insurance on the car.
You have to keep this in mind.  For example,
if brother, I took out a car last year and
he will tell you that you have a one year
comprehensive plan or a zero depth
plan and your 4 year
third party plan gets activated.
Then after that, brother, this happened to you for 5 years.
So if you are
thinking of taking a third party plan then there is
no need for you to take it.  Because here you
already have a 5 year plan.  You should
check with your agency once.  He will
share all the details with you.  But
if your plan expires, then in
that case you will have to purchase insurance again.
I have told you the whole
scenario.  Now you have to see that
if your car is running regularly,
is a little expensive, is new, then brother, in that case
you should take a first party plan.
If your car
is driven very little and is a little old, that is, it is
7-8 years old, then in that
case, if you take a third party plan, it will be enough for
you.  Look, I would
recommend that you take the first party
plan.  Because within the plan it
costs you only ₹400 to ₹500.
But when you go to claim, this
amount will cost you thousands.
So brother, if possible, you should
take the first party plan only.  Let me
show you the live step by step process of
how you can get your
bike or scooter insured while sitting at home.
So friends, first of all I will give you the
direct link to purchase insurance in the
description box below.
Here we are going to use an application.  If
you want, you
can also use their website.  Look, Ekko has the
biggest advantage.  You do
not need to go to any third party i.e. agent
and your insurance is purchased online
and you get to see
your documents in PDF format online.
So brother, it is the best in the
market. For your convenience,
I will give you its direct link
in the description box below.  Now
here you can see that first of all you will have to
enter the number of your bike here so that brother can verify it.
After entering the bike number, you have to
click on the View Prices button.
Now here you will get many search
results.  So here you
can also search your bike and
also confirm here how many cc your bike is.
After searching for bikes etc.,
you can see here that I have a Yamaha
bike and after that you will have to
select its model here.  Meaning,
when was its registration done?  Here
you can see that you have to
select your registration year here.
After selecting the registration year, on the
third number it is asking, brother, what is the
status of your old policy
?  For example, if our
expiry date has not yet passed, then we will
enter 'not expired' here.  If it is going to
expire within 90 days, then here
you have to select Expire in last 90 days.
And if it has
expired more than 90 days, then here you have to
select Expire for More than 90 Days.
You must have understood all the three categories.
If it has not expired under Not Expiry, or it is going to
expire within 90 days, then
here you have to select the second option
and in the third option it is saying
that yours has expired for more than 90 days.
Friends, you have to select this very
carefully.  I told you.
Now here you can see that our
bye number has come here.  After that the
IDB value has come here.  Now I am going to
clear the IDB value for you.
After that your selected plan
tenure will appear here.  1 year, 2 years or 3
years.  Select the plan for whatever number of years you
want to take here.
Once I clear you the IDB
value first.  Here you
can see my IDB value which is the
customized insured value, that is, now first of all
listen to the IDB value.   Let us take
Mann for example.  If
my bike becomes a total loss.
Then my scooter becomes a total loss.
So here I will be
paid the amount equal to my IDV value.  For example, if
your bike catches fire or gets
total damage or some such
accident happens in which
your vehicle gets completely damaged, then in
that case, the maximum amount that
you will be paid is equal to your IDV value.
So here you
can see that in my case, I am getting the minimum
IDV value of ₹32900
and here I am getting the
maximum IDV value of ₹6100, that is,
you have
seen that there is a difference of double here.
Now brother, you have to select this thing
that basically
how much IDV value you want to keep.  I would
say that brother, you should keep your IDV value
maximum because there is
not much change in the premium here,
but if you suffer a total loss in the IDV value, then in
that case your
money becomes half and in
future also, if you sell the IDV value of your vehicle, then
in case of selling, it is also seen
what is your old IDV value and
the higher the IDV value, the
higher will be the value of your vehicle.
So brother, you should also keep your IDV value
maximum.  I select Maximum and
click on Continue.  Now
here you will see that I am being asked to select the plan
1 year, 2 years, 3
years.  And here I have comprehensive
plan and third party plan.  Now look, first of all
notice one thing.  The
comprehensive plan that I am getting here is being offered to me for
₹13.  And the third
party plan is being given to me for ₹714.  That means the
difference is only ₹300.
So I would say that you should select
your comprehensive plan or
first party plan here.   At the same time,
if I tell you about 2 years, then
here you can see that the comprehensive
plan will cost you around ₹1950 and the
third party plan will cost you ₹1428.
And within 3 years you will get ₹2843 and
₹2142, that is, there is not much difference brother.
You
can choose any plan here as per your choice.  Now
listen carefully to what benefits we will get under the comprehensive plan.  For example, if
I select a comprehensive plan for each year here,
then here you
can see what all things are covered under the comprehensive plan.
Whatever the accident, you will be covered.
Cover repair replacement cost if
your bike is damaged in an accident.  That means
if your bike gets damaged in an accident, it will be
covered.  After that, it is
also saying about fire, that is, if your bike or scooter catches fire due to self-ignition,
explosion and lightning, then
that too is 100% covered for you.
After that he is saying that if
your bike gets stolen then
in that case also you will be provided cover here.
But make sure
that you have both the keys of your bike.
Only then will the claim be provided to you here.
After that,
if there is a climate or natural disaster, then in that case
also if your bike etc. gets lost, then
you will get a claim for that also here.
If there is a third party injury or
death, that is, what I was saying, if the
person in front of you gets hit by you
or an accident occurs, then they also
provide this claim.  After that,
if there is any loss to the third party property i.e. the other person, be it a total loss or
anything else, then in that case also a
claim is provided to the other person.
And you should also listen to what these people do not cover.
Such as
non-accidental damages and that is, if there is
wear and tear happening inside your parts.
Like I am riding a bike etc.
and my tyre is worn out, the tube
is worn out or my engine is worn out.  So in
that case, I cannot go to the agency and
say that brother, my first party
means that is insurance and you change my engine.
You must have an accident only
then you are provided with a claim.
After that, if you drive illegally
like violating traffic rules
or if you drink and drive, then the
claim in that case will
not be provided to you.  So friends,
you have to take care of all these things.  I'll
click OK here.  Now
here I will also tell you about one of my third party.
As you can see,
in first party cases, we are
getting maximum benefits but in third party cases,
only if there is third party injury or
death, then he will
get the benefit in that case or if any property of the third party is
damaged, then the other
person will get the claim.  We will
not get anything.  Here you can see
what not cover.  Here, if there is any damage to one's own bike,
it is not covered and
these people also do not cover illegal driving.
So brother, okay, we understand.
I click on the OK button here.
Now friends, here I am purchasing
my plan from a third party just to show you.
Because brother, my
bike etc. remains lying like this.
I am purchasing just to show you.
Basically, if you
do it in comprehensive then the process will be the same.
Here you can see that I finally
click on continue.  Now
friends, my personal
accidental cover is also being pasted here.  So
brother, it is totally your wish.  If you want to take it, you
can take it, otherwise you can skip it.
Here I will finally click on the continue button.
After that, you can see here that
you will have to give some more details.
Like giving your full name,
your email ID, mobile number
, pin code and
if you have GST number here then you can give that also,
otherwise this is optional for you.  Now
after filling all the details, you have to finally
click on the continue button.  Now here you
can see that all your personal details
etc. will be available.  Your bike
number, brand model number, registration year.
So brother, please confirm everything once.
After confirmation, your
bike's overview will appear here and
your premium i.e. insurance will appear here.  Let
us finally
click on the Pay Now button here.  Now friends,
you will get to
see many options to complete the payment.  You
can complete your payment by selecting any method here.  You
can see it here.  Now as soon as your payment
is completed, you will basically have to get your
KYC done here and brother,
your KYC has become mandatory from January 1, 2023.
So brother, let us
click on the Start KYC button here.  Now, to get
KYC done here, you will
first have to verify your PAN card
and here you will have to provide your address proof i.e.
your Aadhar card, driving license or
voter ID card or passport.
So let us
click on Start KYC here.  Now
whatever is your full name on the next page, you have to
give it here.  After that you have to
accept their terms and conditions and
click on the continue button.
After that, on the next page you have to enter your PAN
card number and
also enter your date of birth here.
After that you have to finally proceed.
Now here you can see that in the
name of document verification, we are getting the
option to upload Digilocker or any of our documents etc.
So brother, here we will give you any document of our choice.
Here I
select my driving license.  You
can see that your driving license has to be
uploaded from the front side first.
After that upload it from the back side.  So here
you have to enable the permissions for the camera category
and here you have to
upload your final driving license.
I'll finally click on Use This Photo here.
And here you
can see that whatever our driving license is,
it has been uploaded.  After that
we will have to tell you a few more things here.
Like what is your city?  What
is gender?  Whatever your male or female may be.  You can
tell me as per your wish.  After that you have to
select your relation.  Whoever
you understand here, consider him to be of your normal type.
After that, here you have to
tell the first name and last name of the relation and
finally you have to click on the submit button.
Now friends, finally you can see
that our KYC has been verified.
After KYC is verified, I continue.  As soon as you
continue,
you can see here that our policy will be
issued within 2 to 3 minutes.   That means
friends, our payment will also be complete.
KYC will also be completed and
after that our policy will also be issued.
Now let me wait a little and then
I will tell you.  Friends, here you
can see on the Ekko website itself that the
starting policy date and ending
policy date of our bike are all written here.  I will
basically
blur it out for security reasons.  After that, here you
can see that all your details regarding bike etc.
are provided.  And you
download this policy and
save it in PDF format.  Whenever the
police etc. will check.  Basically she
checks it online only.  But if by
any chance they ask you for it, then if
you show them this PDF, then brother, you will be saved
here.  So friends, this was the complete
process of purchasing bike or insurance through Ekko
and let us assume that
if God forbid any accident happens to you, then
how can you take a claim in that case, let me
tell you a little about the process of this also.
Look basically you do
n't need to call customer care or go anywhere.
You have to take your bike or scooter to the same place
from where you purchased it
i.e. to your showroom.  There will be a Pay Center
Service Center there.  You go there and
basically get them to talk.  Whoever is the
customer care of Ekko etc. will talk to them.
After that the agent etc. comes and verifies whether
you have had an accident
or you are just having fun.
And if an accidental case is made then
your claim is approved.
And as soon as your claim is approved,
your repairing etc. will start immediately.
So friends, this was the complete process of buying
through AGO and then
purchasing the insurance of the scooter.  If you
still have any questions, then
you can ask me in the comment box.
We will meet again in our next
video.  Till then Jai Hind, Jai
Bharat.